apexchange.com 2014-02-10

# AP Exchange

****  
---  
The Associated Press and its affiliates (collectively, “AP”) recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of personal information that may be provided to us by individual users or readers of AP content online. Accordingly, we have adopted a privacy policy to govern how we treat such information. This policy does not apply to information you may provide to us offline. AP may change this privacy policy from time to time, in its sole discretion, and any such changes will become effective when the AP posts the revised privacy policy online. Your continued use of this Web site indicates your consent to AP’s privacy policy and the most current version then in effect.  
**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**  
AP may collect personally identifiable information when you specifically and knowingly provide it to us, such as when you provide your personal information such as your e-mail address, name, phone number or address. 

AP may also collect non-personally identifiable information via the use of cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that are transferred to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies are used to assist you in using site information and content by saving your user preferences. Cookies are also used to collect aggregate information about Web site users on an anonymous basis.   
  
**WHAT DOES THE ASSOCIATED PRESS DO WITH THE INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT?**  
AP will use the personally identifiable information directly submitted by you solely for the purpose for which you have provided it. We may also use the information you provide to us to contact you for reasons related to your original communication to us. Additionally, we may periodically send you promotional e-mail about existing or prospective products and services offered by The Associated Press, as well as to obtain information to better understand our users. We may disclose all of the information we collect about you to our affiliates who offer related goods and services, and to nonaffiliated third parties that perform services on our behalf, including marketing services. 

With regard to non-personally identifiable information, AP is currently using and has contracted with third party vendors to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from our users to administer our content in order to improve our services. We may also perform statistical analysis of user behavior in order to measure interest in our online products and services for product development purposes and to inform advertisers as to how many consumers have seen or clicked their advertisement. We also use demographic and preference information to allow advertisements on our sites to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent, so users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive. 

This information may also be used as part of our demographic research. In this event, the research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. The Associated Press reserves the right and may grant to third parties such right to publish non-personally identifiable, aggregate information regarding our users for promotional purposes and as a representative audience for advertisers. 

AP will not disclose any personally identifiable information about our current or former users to anyone, except as permitted or required by law, or as described herein. AP will endeavor to maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality of the information that we collect online.   
  
**WITH WHOM DOES THE ASSOCIATED PRESS SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT IT COLLECTS?**  
As a general rule, AP will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except under one of the following circumstances: we have your permission; we believe in good faith determines is legally required to be revealed by any relevant statute, regulation, ordinance, rule, administrative or court order, decree, or subpoena; information revealed during the course of AP’s enforcement of the policies and procedures of the website; information that we determine must be disclosed to correct what we believe to be false or misleading information or to address activities that we believe to be manipulative, deceptive or otherwise a violation of law; where you are otherwise notified at the time we collect the data; where we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; when disclosed to an affiliate of AP or when such disclosure is made subject to confidentiality restrictions in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange, or other disposition (whether of assets, stock, or otherwise) of all or a portion of the business conducted by the web sites to which the AP privacy policy applies. AP may share the non-personally identifiable information that AP gathers, in aggregate form only, with advertisers and other partners. AP may use services provided by third parties, including, without limitation, Chartbeat (“Chartbeat”), Quantcast ("Quantcast"), and Google Analytics (“Google”) to collect non-personally identifiable information on pages that contain AP's news content. Please refer to Chartbeat's privacy policy at <http://www.chartbeat.com/privacy>, Quantcast's privacy policy at <http://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/privacy-policy>, and Google’s privacy policy at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html>, for further information concerning each entity's use of non-personally identifiable information. AP is not responsible for any actions or policies of any third-party service providers, including, without limitation, Chartbeat, Quantcast, and/or Google. This information collected by third-party service providers is used by AP and is disclosed to AP's advertising partners so that they can determine the efficacy of their campaigns. None of the information collected or reported to our advertising partners identifies you.   
**THIRD PARTY SITES**  
This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information, or other practices of any third parties, including, without limitation, any third party operating any site to which the any AP website contains a link. The inclusion of a link in any AP website does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us.   
**INTERNATIONAL USAGE**  
If you are located outside of the United States, please note that the information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using this web site, you consent to this transfer.   
**NOTE REGARDING USE OF SITES BY CHILDREN**  
None of our AP websites is directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13).   
**HOW DOES A USER CHANGE OR UPDATE THEIR INFORMATION?**  
If you have any questions or concerns about the AP privacy policy or would like the personally identifiable information that you have provided to The Associated Press removed from our files, please contact AP at: [apdigitalsupport@ap.org](mailto:apdigitalsupport@ap.org) or please write to the following address:   
Privacy Policy Questions

The Associated Press

450 West 33rd Street

New York, NY 10001
